Have you seen your father?
Your little cousins
have lost their mother.
They could use a kind word.
I have an equal claim to sympathy.
- Jace.
- We should be at Harrenhal.
mourning Lord Lyonel and Ser Harwin.
It would not be appropriate.
The Velaryons are our kin
and the Strongs are not.
Look at me.
Do you understand?
Hand turns loom.
spool of green. spool of black.
dragons of flesh
weaving dragons of thread.
Hand turns loom. spool of green...
- We have nothing in common.
- She's our sister.
- You marry her. then.
- I would perform my duty.
- if mother had only betrothed us.
- If only.
It would strengthen the family.
Keep our Valyrian blood pure.
- She's an idiot.
- She's your future queen.
We actually do have
one thing in common.
We both fancy creatures
with very long legs.
Wench!
- Another!
- Aegon.
...dragon's flesh.
weaving dragons of thread.
Lyonel Strong's son's
been staring at you
since the moment we arrived. Your Grace.
Unabashedly.
It is only a look of pride. Ser Criston.
Larys is the new Lord of Harrenhal.
Both my seat and High Tide
will be yours one day. Lucerys.
Your brother will be king. of course.
He'll sit on endless
councils and ceremonies.
but Lord of the Tides rules the sea.
Sorry.
I don't want it.
It's your birthright. lad.
If I'm the Lord of Driftmark.
it means everyone's dead.
- I'm very sorry. my princess.
- Thank you. Thank you.
Grandma...
I don't want Mother to be gone.
Retrieve your patron.
Brother.
Your girls are the very
image of their mother.
A comfort and an anguish.
as I well remember.
The gods can be cruel.
It seems they've been
especially cruel to you.
Yes.
You should return with us
to King's Landing.
It's time that you came home.
Pentos is my home...
- and that of my children.
- Daemon...
I know we've had our differences.
but let them pass with the years.
There's a place for you in my court
if that's something you should need.
I need nothing.
Brother.
I'm sorry for your loss. my prince.
No matter how fat the leech grows.
it always wants for another meal.
Go to bed.
- But. Mother--
- Go to bed.
I'm going to bed. Aemma.
Shall I see after Queen Alicent.
Your Grace?
No. Ser Harrold.
You have the night's watch. Ser Criston.
Lord Commander.
Brother?
Get to bed.
She wanted to come home
and he denied her.
Daemon did
what he thought best.
Daemon only ever does
what is best for Daemon.
Laena needed our maesters.
The surgeons in Pentos
are as well-trained
as our maesters.
You are looking to place blame
for an act of the gods.
Mayhaps the gods have scorned us...
for our insatiable pride.
The crown was yours
until those fools at the Great Council
plucked it from your head.
Is it such a terrible thing
for your husband to wish to win it back?
Tonight of all nights.
let us lay aside this falsehood.
It is not justice for
your wife that drives you.
It is your own ambition.
'Tis desire for the throne.
if not for yourself.
then for the scions of your house.
I gave up the idea of wearing a crown
a generation ago.
It is you. lord husband.
who refuses to abandon this pursuit.
even now. at the cost of our children.
What is this brief mortal life...
if not the pursuit of legacy?
Legacy may be why you
live your life. Corlys.
I want Driftmark to pass through
Laena's line to Baela.
To true Velaryon blood.
Declare it now.
while all are gathered here.
and we will say that is how
we will honor Laena's memory.
And disinherit our son?
He will be the King Consort.
His son will one day
sit the Iron Throne.
You would have me cast
an even darker shadow
over those little boys
than already exists.
We are alone here. husband.
You can speak the plain truth
as we both know it.
Rhaenyra's children
are not of your blood.
But Laena's are.
They are her legacy.
History does not remember blood.
It remembers names.
Laenor has been restless for years.
but now. he will be useless.
Or worse.
I know better than anyone
that our marriage is a farce.
But I at least make the effort
to maintain appearances.
You have more to lose.
Yes. well. that has been
my lot since my father named me heir.
We did try...
to conceive a child.
We performed our duty as best we could.
But to no avail.
There was no joy in it.
I found that elsewhere.
- It felt good to be desired.
- Mmm.
I understand Ser Harwin was quite...
devoted to you.
Yes. he was.
And I trusted him.
Should've forbidden Ser Harwin
from returning to the Riverlands.
Harren's curse
is said to be as strong now
as it was after the Conquest.
That's a ghost story.
one Ser Otto and the Queen
would gladly exploit.
I do not believe Alicent
capable of cold murder.
Each of us is capable of depravity.
And more than you would believe.
I believe it of you.
If you're accusing me of some depravity.
you'll need to be more specific.
I've been alone.
- You abandoned me.
I spared you.
- You were a child.
Yes.
Yes. I was a child.
And look at what my life
became without you.
Droll tragedy.
And I wonder what you
think of mine by comparison?
I know little of it.
Did you love her?
We were happy enough.
Well. that in itself
is a great achievement.
- I am sorry.
- Don't be.
I am at least allowed
to mourn my losses.
Rhaenyra.
I'm no longer a child.
I want you.
Fuck.
Dohaeras!
Dohaeras. Vhagar! Lykiri!
Lykiri!
Lykiri.
Soves!
Dohaeras. Vhagar! Soves!
Yeah!
Jace. Jace.
Jace. wake up. Wake up.
- Someone stole Vhagar.
- What?
Who is it?
Jace. what are we doing?
- It's him.
- It's me.
- Vhagar is my mother's dragon.
Your mother's dead.
- And Vhagar has a new rider now.
- She was mine to claim.
Then you should've claimed her!
Maybe your cousins
can find you a pig to ride.
It would suit you.
Come at me again
and I'll feed you to my dragon!
You will die screaming in flames
just as your father did!
Bastards.
My father's still alive.
He doesn't know. does he. Lord Strong?
Jace!
Cease this at once!
Get away!
My prince. my prince. Let me see.
Gods be good.
How could you allow
such a thing to happen?
I will have answers.
The princes were supposed
to be abed. my king.
Who had the watch?
Young Prince was attacked by
his own cousins. Your Grace.
You swore oaths to protect
and defend my blood!
I'm very sorry. Your Grace.
The Kingsguard has never had
to defend princes from princes.
- Your Grace.
- That is no answer!
It will heal. will it not. maester?
The flesh will heal.
But the eye is lost. Your Grace.
Where were you?
Me?
- Ow! What was that for?
- That was nothing
compared to the abuse
your brother suffered
while you were drowning
in your cups. you fool.
What is the meaning of this?
Baela. Rhaena!
What happened?
Jace?
Luke!
- Show me. Show me.
- Who did this?
- They attacked me!
- He attacked Baela!
- He broke Luke's nose!
He stole my mother's dragon!
- Enough.
He was gonna kill Jace!
- I didn't do anything!
- Enough--
It should be my son telling the tale!
- He called us--
- Silence!
He called us bastards.
Aemond...
I will have the truth of what happened.
- Now.
- What else is there to hear?
Your son has been maimed.
Her son is responsible.
- It was a regrettable accident.
Accident?
The Prince Lucerys brought
a blade to the ambush.
He meant to kill my son.
It was my sons who were attacked
and forced to defend themselves.
Vile insults were levied against them.
What insults?
The legitimacy of my sons' birth
was put loudly to question.
- What?
- He called us bastards.
My sons are in line
to inherit the Iron Throne. Your Grace.
This is the highest of treasons.
Prince Aemond must be sharply questioned
so we might learn where
he heard such slanders.
Over an insult?
My son has lost an eye.
You tell me. boy.
Where did you hear this lie?
The insult
was training yard bluster.
- The lot of boys. It was nothing.
- Aemond...
I asked you a question.
Where is Ser Laenor. I wonder?
The boys' father?
Perhaps he might have
something to say in the matter.
Yes. Where is Ser Laenor?
I do not know. Your Grace.
I... could not find sleep.
I had gone out to walk.
Entertaining his young squires.
I would venture.
Aemond...
look at me.
Your king demands an answer.
Who spoke these lies to you?
It was Aegon.
Me?
And you. boy?
Where did you hear such calumnies?
Aegon! Tell me the truth of it!
We know. Father.
Everyone knows.
Just look at them.
This interminable infighting must cease!
All of you!
We are family!
Now make your apologies
and show good will to one another.
Your father. your grandsire.
your king demands it!
That is insufficient.
Aemond has been damaged.
permanently. my king.
"Good will" cannot make him whole.
I know. Alicent.
but I cannot restore his eye.
No. because it's been taken.
- What would you have me do?
- There is a debt to be paid.
I shall have one of her
son's eyes in return.
- My dear wife.
- He is your son. Viserys.
Your blood.
Do not... allow your temper
to guide your judgment.
If the King will not
seek justice. the Queen will.
Ser Criston...
bring me the eye of Lucerys Velaryon.
- Mother!
Alicent.
He can choose which eye to keep.
a privilege he did not grant my son.
You will do no such thing.
- Stay your hand.
- No. you are sworn to me!
As your protector. my queen.
Alicent. this matter... is finished.
Do you understand?
And let it be known.
anyone whose tongue dares
to question the birth
of Princess Rhaenyra's sons
should have it removed.
Thank you. Father.
- Your Grace. Stay with the King!
- Alicent!
Hold your approach!
Do not. Ser Criston!
Alicent!
- Do not. Ser Criston!
No!
Stay your hand. Cole!
- You've gone too far.
- I?
What have I done but
what was expected of me?
Forever upholding the kingdom.
the family. the law.
While you flout it all
to do as you please.
Alicent. let her go!
Where is duty? Where is sacrifice?
It's trampled under
your pretty foot again.
Release the blade. Alicent.
And now you take my son's eye.
and to even that. you feel entitled.
Exhausting. wasn't it?
Hiding beneath the cloak
of your own righteousness.
But now they see you
as you are.
Do not mourn me. Mother.
It was a fair exchange.
I may have lost an eye...
but I gained a dragon.
This proceeding is at an end.
The Hand. Your Grace.
Say your piece.
Now. what piece is that?
I've conducted myself in a manner...
unbefitting my station.
Or any other.
I lost composure.
assaulted the Princess.
Already the word is spreading.
the gossip speculating
that I've gone mad.
All true.
I disgraced myself.
And ensured my husband's favor
will forever rest on her.
And yet...
I've never seen that side of you.
my daughter.
I even doubted its existence.
- It was an ugly thing. I regret it.
- We play an ugly game.
And now. for the first time.
I see that you have
the determination to win it.
- Rhaenyra--
You see her for what she is.
What the King's stubbornness
has wrought.
- What will he say to me?
He'll forgive you.
What else can he do?
Now go to him. be penitent.
plead the injury to your son.
Keep a grip on your passions.
And I promise you. in time.
you and I together will prevail.
What that rogue Aemond has done
in winning Vhagar to our side.
The boy was right.
It's worth a thousand times
the price he paid.
You will scar. but the wound will heal.
Valyrian steel cuts clean.
Gods.
Is everyone all right?
A broken nose is the worst.
Thank you. maester.
Leave us.
You as well.
You've already found
enough trouble today.
Yes. Mother.
I should've been there.
Those should be our house words.
I have fought dreadful enemies.
but I could not defend my dear sister
far from home and in agony.
- I could not defend you.
- Sit down.
Aemond called our sons bastards.
I have failed you. Rhaenyra.
Our marriage...
I tried.
Our boys...
- I do love them.
- I know.
Deeply.
But I have not. mayhaps...
loved them enough.
I had hoped to bear your children.
The few times we lay together.
Things might've been different.
I hate the gods
for making me as they did.
I do not.
You are an honorable man
with a good heart.
It's a rare thing.
We made an arrangement
all those years ago
to do our duty and...
yet explore happiness.
But there are times
I think when these things
cannot mutually exist.
Ser Qarl will return soon
to the fighting in the Stepstones.
But I recommit myself to you.
And to strengthening our house
as we prepare you for your ascension.
I will raise our sons
to be princes of the realm.
- Laenor--
- You deserve better
than what I have been.
You deserve a husband.
I've asked them to have wine ready
for you on the ship.
To help you sleep.
I'm so sorry.
Viserys...
We will speak no more of it.
Fire is such strange power.
Everything that House Targaryen
possesses is owed to it.
Yet it has cost us both what we loved.
Perhaps the Velaryons
knew the truth of it.
The sea is the better ally.
Fire is a prison.
The sea offers an escape.
A perversion of justice.
The young Prince...
defiled.
An outrage.
Indeed.
If it's an eye you want to balance
the scales. I am your servant.
That will not be necessary.
But your devotion
has not gone unnoticed.
These are dangerous times.
The day will doubtless come
when I require such a friend.
With not only skill
but discretion as well.
I shall await your call. my queen.
I need you. Uncle.
We could not marry
unless Laenor were dead.
I know.
I've heard about your exploits
in the Stepstones.
Ser Qarl.
Said to be a knight of remarkable skill.
You flatter me. m'lord.
But alas. common-born.
You're a landless knight
with a lord's taste.
Ser Laenor's been kind to me.
Do you know...
there are places
across the Narrow Sea...
where it doesn't matter
what a man's name is?
Only how much gold he possesses.
What are you asking of me. m'lord?
A quick death.
One with witnesses.
I will not be a tyrant.
And rule through terror.
A tyrant rules only through terror.
If the King isn't feared.
he is powerless.
If you are to be a strong queen.
you must cultivate
love and respect. yes.
but your subjects must fear you.
Who let you in here?
Why are you in my father's hall?
You have always looked down on me.
I do love Laenor.
Then grant him this kindness.
Set him free.
You forget yourself.
My lord. Please!
I'll alert the guards!
This will cost Lord Corlys
and Princess Rhaenys
their only remaining child.
And the realm will whisper
that I was somehow responsible.
No!
Let them whisper.
How did you let this happen?
In my fucking hall?
Tell me!
We will know
the truth of it and our enemies won't.
They will fear what else
we might be capable of.
Hen lantoti anogar.
Va syndroti. Vaedroma.
Mero perzot gihoti.
Eledroma iarza sir.
Izuli ampa perzi.
Prumi lanti seteksi.
Hen jeny mazilarion.
Qelossa ozundesi.
Syndroro ono jedo.
Ry kivia mazvestraksi.